Ruiqi Kong

User Experience Design

(+86) 153 8895 3996 ruiqikong@gmail.com sakamotomari.github.io I enjoy landing design solutions from chaotic needs. With my background in information technology, Master's education in HCI, and experience in interaction design, I am competent in the whole process of design.

SKILLS

Design

User research

Sketching Wireframing

Prototyping

UI design

User testing

Software

Illustrator

Photoshop

Axure

XD

Tableau

JASP

NVivo

Programming

C++, Java HTML/CSS, js Python, Matlab

LANGUAGES

Mandarin (native)
English (excellent command)
Japanese (good command)

HOBBIES

Doodling
Writing articles
Experiencing stories and
music
Designing graphics
Learning languages
Kendo

EDUCATION

University College London | UK

09/2018 - 09/2019

- M.S. Human-Computer Interaction
- Studied Interaction Science and Design systematically

Hunan University | China

09/2014 - 06/2018

- B.E. Digital Media Technology, 1st
- Interaction Designer/Graphic Designer in 3 associations
- Psychology Commissioner in class

EXPERIENCE

Product Operation Intern

05/2017 - 11/2017

www.xiaopiu.com, Beijing Xueyun Ruichuang Technology

- Analysed the information architecture and UI modules of 4 mobile Apps based on user scenarios
- Created templates of UI modules and pages of Apps which were reused for over 2000 times

Interaction Designer

10/2015 - 03/2017

Development Centre, Yiban Student Studio, Hunan University

- Designed the interaction flow and UI of 3 applications, of which "Flea Market" was iterated twice and published within campus
- Assisted in promoting projects, analysed tasks and balanced technical restrictions with team

PROJECTS

ICU Dashboard prototype improvement 02/2019 - 03/2019

Design possibilities of a dashboard prototype that were proposed based on research about user needs and work flow of ICU of UCL Hospital

Codudo: Interaction system design 10/2018 - 12/2018

An interactive system where users could create a large painting together through doodling individually, which aims at solving the problem of lacking senses of belonging among international students

Leode: mobile App design

07/2017 - 08/2017

A double-ended mobile App that explores the guide mode of "traveller-local resident", to solve the problem of having no time to plan for a trip